Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 24.
We will continue whether recursion and we are asked to explain the functionality of the functions the
following functions like the end function one.
Took in the perimeter into X and Y and return and.
If X equal equal to zero return, why else return function won with X minus one plus and the second
parameter is x plus y?
So we this is the function one recursion we are calling again and again until having X equal equal to
zero.
This is the stopping condition.
OK.
I need from you to post the video and think about.
Please, both the video and solve it by their own and commend the solution in the comments below in
order to like it, make discussion and help you to solve and concentrate on the points, you may make
mistakes in on it.
OK.
So where do your comments?
I will start you're like solving this function.
And by the way, this is one of the questions that is like asked in the interviews, OK?
Function of F1.
I told you in there as a flow, it's solve problem solving flow chart lesson.
How to make and how to solve the problems by taking a real exam.
OK, so take a real example and on on a paper and you will get that like an idea how to solve like these
algorithms?
OK, take one and two and three.
And what?
What you have to figure out how the algorithm works and how the behavior and get the pattern.
So.
Without wasting much time, we will start into F function one.
I will take, for example, x equal to four, so I will call function.
Function.
Three, I will took three and y is equal to four.
OK, now if X equals equal to zero, no X is not equal to zero, it's equal to three.
So it will not execute this.
It will execute this return function.
F1, its function F1.
I will call function F1 again.
Function F1 and X minus one, which is two and with X plus one, which is seven.
OK.
Again, half of two goes here.
It starts executing if Block X equal equal to zero, no else return function f one x.
This is will return F1 function one weather two minus one is one, and x plus y is equal to seven.
OK, so.
The trick here is that X and Y, X and Y are not three and four here, if there's two and seven, because
if we substitute above two at seven, so x plus y with this example, this function despite we have
yet increased decreased x by one.
This is for the local and local argument, but x it kept as the past x so two plus seven is equal to
nine.
OK.
Again, function one is being executed.
Return function one with one and nine x equal equal to zero.
No.
It will return function f one function f one.
This is F function and one.
With X minus one one minus one is equal to zero nine.
Plus one is equal to 10.
OK, so this is how it will return again.
It goes up if X equals equal to zero.
Yes.
So return why this is the function with party meet, there are zero x and Y equal to 10.
It were returned y so y here is equal to 10.
So function one.
Here is 10.
Okay.
This is how it works.
This is how the functionality of this function works.
So like, these exercises are very important to understand the recursion.
And that algorithm behind that expression and the way and the pattern behind the recursion.
So these exercises, I hope you solve them and send us the comments and let us discuss what you may
encounter some problems.